Guide to the Business Collection 1767-1999 MS008
Cornwall Historical Society
Business Collection
1767-1999
Cornwall Historical Society
Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941
Gannett, Michael R. (Michael Ross), 1919-
MS008
1 linear foot (2 boxes)
This collection contains items related to business activity in Cornwall.
Provenance
The items in this collection were initially collected by local historian E.C. Starr, but organized and expanded upon by former Cornwall Historical Society president Michael Gannett.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The documents include both items related to businesses located in Cornwall, as well as non-local businesses that Cornwall residents patronized.
Sources:
Scope and Content Note
The documents include both items related to businesses located in Cornwall, as well as non-local businesses that Cornwall residents patronized from 1767 to 1999. The items in this collection were initially collected by local historian E.C. Starr, but organized and expanded upon by former Cornwall Historical Society president Michael Gannett.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series, businesses located in Cornwall and businesses not located in Cornwall, then alphabetically and chronologically within each series.
The files are grouped into 2 series:
Cornwall Businesses
Non-Cornwall Businesses
Cornwall (Conn.)--history.; Cornwall (Conn.); Correspondence; Bills of exchange; Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941; Gannett, Michael R. (Michael Ross), 1919-; Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941; Gannett, Michael R. (Michael Ross), 1919-; Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941; Gannett, Michael R. (Michael Ross), 1919-
- Cornwall Businesses and Businesspeople
  - Else Adler’s Farm bill, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - J.A. Babcock newspaper dealer receipt, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - L.J. Beeman Plumbing and Gutter Work receipt, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - George H. Beers bills for explosives, 1909; , undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - M. Beers Low receipt for tobacco license, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - M. Beers Son advertisement, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Edward W. Bennett receipt for potatoes, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Peter Bierce’s liquor license, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - W.H. Breen General Merchandise receipts, 1912-1926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Edward D. Cartwright automotive business letterhead, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Edward D. Cartwright advertisement for Nash Sport Car De Luxe, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Business card for James Clark’s horse shoeing business, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Copy of bill from James Clark to John Harrison, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Coltsfoot Farm bills, 1889-1923 (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
  - Community Service, Inc. letter to customers, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Flier for Cornwall Bridge Days, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter sent to Cornwall Bridge Iron Company agent Peter Bierce, from customer in Boston, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cornwall Bridge Iron Company price quotes, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cornwall Bridge Iron Company bill, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cornwall Bridge Pottery advertisements, 1987-1991; , undated (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
  - Cornwall Bridge Pottery brochure, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Cornwall Bridge Pottery Christmas letter, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cornwall Bridge Pottery photograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Cornwall Creamery Company stock records, 1891-1896 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cornwall Creamery Company bills for Cochrane Bros., 1898 (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
  - Cornwall Package Store newsletter, The Cornwall Wine Press, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Cornwall Package Store letter sent to Michael Gannett, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Cornwall Manufacturing Company shares, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Letter regarding the Cornwall Water Company sent to Theodore Sturges by secretary E. Cartwright, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Cornwall Water Company rates and rules, 1942; , undated (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
  - Cornwall Yellow Pages, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
  - Covered Bridge Building and Hardware Supplies, Inc. opening announcement, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Covered Bridge Inn advertisements, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 40-41)
  - Cream Hill Farm milk bill for H.M. Pratt, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Cream Hill Farm receipt sent to Lewis Gannett, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - George S. Crosby builder’s bill, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - D S Building Company bills, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Dark Entry Forest, Inc. letterhead, with notes on organization, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Elm Valley Farm bills of E.D. Cartwright, 1925-1932 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - C.W. Everett flour, grain, and feed dealer bill, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Everett House advertisement, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Freshfields Restaurant letter to the community, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - J. George Fritz woodworking bill, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Frost Calhoun business card, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Martin D. Gold, used books and antiques dealer, receipt, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Hall’s Garage advertisement, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Harrison Company bill, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - C.W. Hart bills for E.D. Cartwright, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - List of Havess Farm shareholders, 1809 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Hayloft Book Print Shop receipt of Mr. Gannett, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Hayloft Book Print Shop advertisement, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - R.W. Horner bill and receipt for carpentry work, 1927-1935 (Box 1, Folder 60-61)
  - Bill of Samuel Horsford, 1788 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Housatonic Valley Furniture Shop letter opener, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Map showing the location of Housatonic Valley Industries, undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Housatonic Valley Rug Shop flier, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Impact Manufacturing Company news story, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Interstate Refuse Collection letter to customers, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Account books attributed to Seymour Johnson’s dairy business, 1838-1861 (Box 1, Folder 68-71)
  - Landmark Real Estate letter to Cornwall residents, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Letter to lead mine proprietors in Cornwall and Kent from Michael Judah, 1767 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - List of bushels of seed sold from unknown dealer, 1782-1783 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Little Guild of St. Francis newspaper story, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - J. Mallinson receipt for pocket scissors, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence between J. Mallinson Shear Company and Andrew M. Clark, 1902-1903 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - “Wanted” notice for J. Mallinson Shear Co. scissors, undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Charles C. Marsh receipt and bill, 1914-1920 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Mansion House receipt, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Mansion House bill, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Map of Cornwall listing local businesses, undated (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Mariner’s Compass designed by Caleb Jones, undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Matthews 1812 House letter to customers, undated (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Geo. F. Merz Tin and Sheet Metal Work bill for Whiting Wilcox, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Milkhouse Pottery advertisements, undated (Box 1, Folder 86-87)
  - Modern Electric Shop receipt of E.D. Cartwright, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Modern Electric Shop memo book, undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Modern Electric Shop stationary, undated (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Mohawk Mountain ski area brochure, undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - H.W. Odell, general merchandise, receipt, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - William Oliver blacksmithing bills, 1898-1903 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - William Oliver receipt of E.D. Cartwright, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - James Osborne, painter, receipt, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Parsonage House business card, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Phillips Dairy Inc. bill with H.M. Pratt, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Woodworking pattern book of Edward Pikosky, 1950-1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Pine Villa letter sent to Mr. Hart, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ezra D. Pratt patent for improved bee hive feed boxes, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Pratt and Foster receipts with J. Scoville and Ezra D. Pratt, 1854-1860 (Box 2, Folder 10'-11)
  - A.B. Reed meat dealer bill, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - River Valley Spirits advertisement, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Miner P. Rogers receipt for fabric, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - W.L. Rogers bill and receipt, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - R. Scoville receipts, 1878-1882 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - W.P. Shurtleff painting and paper hanging bills of E.W. Cartwright, 1922-1938 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Smith Brothers Country Store receipt of H.M. Pratt, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Smith Sons dry goods bills, 1886-1905 (Box 2, Folder 20-23)
  - Smith Sons letter, regarding a small fire, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Smith Sons receipts, 1882-1894 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Southern New England Telephone Company contract, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Southern New England Telephone Company bill, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Program for cornerstone ceremony of the Southern New England Telephone Company, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Strip of paper listing Cornwall businesses, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Sturges Son receipts, 1923-1935 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Sturges Son calendar, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Sturges Son day planners, undated (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
  - Sturges Son cards sent to customers, undated (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
  - Lawrence C. Sturges obituaries, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Theo. Sturges bill and receipt, 1903-1907 (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
  - Stuart Grant Antiques letter to Michael Gannett, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - The Success Source newsletter of DNA Fischer, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Tavern at the Inn advertisement, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - The Telephone Bulletin with cover image of Cornwall covered bridge, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Geo. H. Trieschman blacksmithing receipt and bill, 1899; , undated (Box 2, Folder 43-44)
  - Internal Revenue License of Isaac Wedge, 1866 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - West Cornwall Antique Center advertisement, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Editorials regarding proposed West Cornwall Bar at the Emporium, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - West Cornwall business listing, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - West Cornwall Merchants Association walking map of West Cornwall, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - George D. Wilbur, electrical contractor, receipt, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - C.E. Wilcox Sons bills, 1886-1917 (Box 2, Folder 51-53)
  - The Wish House sale announcement, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - The Wish House brochure, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - The Wish House expansion announcement, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Yutzler Store bills, 1923-1995 (Box 2, Folder 57-61)
  - Yutzler Store receipts, 1917-1919; , undated (Box 2, Folder 62-63)
  - F.A. Yutzler Co. registration letter to Dairymen’s League, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Yutzler Store announcement regarding change in ownership, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Yutzler Store letters to customers, 1977; , undated (Box 2, Folder 66-67)
  - Yutzler Country Store milk dealer’s license, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Yutzler Country Store tobacco licenses, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 69-70)
  - Yutzler Country Store patent medicine license, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Yutzler Store holiday greeting cards, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - F.A. Yutzler Co. business cards, undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Unknown receipt for fabric, ribbon, and thread, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Non-Cornwall Businesses
  - Barney and Berry skate company catalogue and advertisement, 1884; , undated (Box 2, Folder 75-76)
  - Book of exchange rates from British to Dutch, Hamburgh, and French currency, undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - The Bradley Smith Company bill of W.J. Wilcox, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Cable Sons advertisements for pianos, undated (Box 2, Folder 79-80)
  - Dana’s Bull Nose Punch advertisement, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - W.C. Dusenberry Co advertisement, 1828 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - H.W. John’s Manufacturing Co. sample book of asbestos liquid paint and price index, 1883-1884 (Box 2, Folder 83-84)
  - Joseph Ketchum’s bill for Daniel Brown, 1787 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - The King’s Insurance Company pamphlet, undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Kodak Film Developing ephemera of J.M. Manning, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Lakeville Frame Shop business card, undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Letter sent to E.C. Starr from the New Manufacturing Company chief engineer, Frederick G. Hughes, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - William Rogers Manufacturing Co. advertisement, undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Torrington Creamery bills for W.J. Wilcox, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Clayton J. Walter Insurance receipt of Whiting J. Wilcox, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 92)